Dear Sir /Madam,

I am pleased to apply for the role of teacher at your institution. I am currently working as an English teacher for grades 7 and 8 at The Schram Academy, an international school.

I have robust experience in applying a wide variety of teaching methodologies and techniques. During my employment at The Schram Academy, I have

- consistently worked my way up the institution, from K.G to primary.
- succeeded as a resource consultant (2019–2021) by being responsible for designing and delivering extra scholastic activities in English to classes I to VII related to LSRW skills in the target language.
- performed as a subject coordinator, assisting and supporting other teachers with different teaching activities. Observing classes and mentoring teachers on the effectiveness of their pedagogy, organising cluster meetings to discuss department-related issues.
- worked on my writing muscles by contributing to the school souvenir and delivering content and scripts to school functions and celebrations.

My strong initiative, exceptional organisational skills, and ability to cater to a diverse culture allow me to play a crucial role in a dynamic learning environment. With my history of team collaboration, I can be an asset to your institution.

For further information, please refer to my resume.

With sincere gratitude,

Hema Manohar.

Resume

Name: Hema Manohar M.S, D.El.Ed, CELTA.

Address: Newry Shanmitha, 3B,206, Bharathiyar st,Jalladianpet,Chennai-100.

E-mail: hmanohar2020@gmail.com Phone no: 9500031457, 9500041458.

Objective: To orchestrate and empower fellow teachers and students by leading, building trust, inspiring and facilitating learning.

Work Experience:

Institution	Position held	Tenure
The Schram Academy	English Teacher	2021-2022
The Schram Academy	Resource consultant.	2019- 2021
The Schram Academy	English teacher.	2012-2019
The Sprout play school	Coordinator.	2009-10

Educational qualification:

- A certificate in English Language teaching for adults(CELTA) from Cambridge University in 2020.
- A diploma in elementary education (D.El.Ed) from NIOS between 2017-2019.
- A Course on all 3 modules of TKT(Teaching knowledge test) from British council in 2014.
- A P.G diploma in teacher training and montessori from SSV in 2012.
- A postgraduate degree in Information Technology and Management from Kamaraj University, Madurai between 2000-2002.